welcome ladies and gentlemen to the
advanced Market structure video now
we're going to get started right away
this chart that you have in front of you
right now very clearly you can tell that
this is
gbpnzd and that we are currently on the
4-Hour time frame and the market
structure that you have in front of you
is indicating to you that this Market is
bearish but as soon as I snap my fingers
my editors have just zoomed in to only
the chart and now I can flicker down a
couple pairs and now you no longer know
know what Market this is or what time
frame we are on all that you do see is
that you have Market structure in front
of you so it does not matter what
currency pair you have what stock pair
you have what crypto markets in front of
you binaries anything that has a chart
has Market structure you can't tell what
Market this is and you can't tell what
time frame this is what you could tell
is that this Market is bullish or
bearish Market structure is Absolut
absolutely everything in the market and
in this video I'm going to be explaining
to you the advanced way on how to look
at Market structure and not care about
the time frame and not care about the
markets behind the market structure
welcome to the advanced Market structure
video oh and by the way this Market is
audusd and it's on the 4our I can go
back in and I can change a couple
different pairs and I can change to a
different time frame and I can snap my
fingers again and we're add a new
currency pair and now here you can't
tell if we're on the higher time frame
or what pair we on and this is actually
nzdusd on the 15-minute time frame
Market structure is key everything else
does not matter so let's begin with the
most important thing when identifying
Market structure which is going to be
higher highs and higher lows if a market
is bullish a market is consisted of
higher highs and higher lows it is
impossible and I I cannot stress this as
much as I wish I can it is is impossible
to have a bullish Market without a
higher high or a higher low a higher
high tends to be the highest points of
where that current market structure is
and the last higher low is the last
higher low not the highest low or the
most low low I don't know why people
confuse this and this is a advanced
video so I want you guys to understand
the importance of reading this correctly
because it's going to be a lot easier
for you to enter trades and capital ize
off of them in the future so we know
that this is the higher high and this is
the higher low the market will remain
bullish as long as we stay in between
this higher high and higher low the
moment we body close above or under this
line is when we will have a shift in the
market if we close Above This higher
high that means we've created a new
higher high and the higher low has to be
the last higher low the simplest way of
reading that is going to the highest
point and I like using my snake trick
where I simply get this body of the
snake and at the moment that the snake
has a sharp turn that is the most higher
low a snake when it wants to move in a
different direction it goes and then it
turns and then it turns and then it
turns the market when it wants to move
in a different direction it turns as
well so this is the market turning from
being this high higher low to then this
higher low and once again as long as the
market stays in between this higher high
and this higher low the market will be
bullish now we can get as close as we
can as we did to this point right here
and we still would be bullish remember
we are only shifting Market if we body
Candlestick close above or if we close
under if I take this to the chart for
example let's say that this would be the
higher high right here and that this
would be the higher low right here this
is the head of the snake at this point
right here the snake goes it turned then
it keeps going down this is the higher
low we do not place the higher high or
higher low at the Wicks of a certain
move or at the Wicks of a certain move
higher highs and higher lows are placed
at the bodies of the candlestick because
this is where the market structure is if
I were to come into here and I would
erase the candlesticks and go to the
line chart you can see that the
structure is at this higher low and at
this higher high if we go back to the
candlesticks you can see that the Wicks
are just the trail of where the market
went but it's not the actual Market
structure so once again it is impossible
to have a bullish Market without a
higher high or a higher low the market
will remain bullish as long as we stay
in between the higher high and higher
low the moment we body close above we
have then created a new higher high and
we must have a new higher low once we
have a new higher high it is impossible
to have a new higher high without a new
higher low and as long as we don't body
close above either one of these lines
this Market will remain bullish until we
close above or we close under and that
is one of the main issues with Traders
nowadays because they just pull up to a
chart and because they see the overall
movement heading up or the overall
movement heading down they think a
market is bullish or a market is bearish
and that cannot be further from the
truth this is one of the biggest
mistakes that Traders make and say they
are not analyzing the market structure
correctly they are not analyzing the
trend of the market correctly the
simplest example that I can leave of
this is let's say that you you are
hunting and a hunter in order for it to
catch its prey they follow footsteps or
the tracks of an animal if you aren't
reading correctly the tracks of an
animal if it's going in one direction or
if it was coming towards this direction
you can completely be walking the
opposite way of where the animal is
going and this is exactly what people do
when they analyze the markets
incorrectly they can assume that they're
reading it correctly but are actually
doing the complete opposite and just
digging themselves in a deeper hole and
this right here is a perfect example up
to every single example that I have just
showing you guys right now this Market
was bullish until we body Candlestick
closed under this higher low if you're a
begin a Trader and I show you this chart
like this you'll probably say that this
Market is bullish because you would look
at it and you would take an assumption
that overall this is bullish because
it's just heading to the upside but that
cannot be further from the truth why
because this once upon a time was the
higher high and then this was the higher
low the fact that the market has now
body Candlestick close under this area
means that this Market is now bearish we
have shifted the market structure from
being bullish to bearish so so has the
trend the trend is identified by the
market structure without Market
structure you cannot identify the trend
without Footprints or tracks when you go
hunting you cannot tell if there's an
animal there and where it is going it is
absolutely impossible is absolutely
impossible to tell this is bullish
bearish without the market structure so
since this has now created a new lower
low this becomes the new lower low and
you must need a new lower high it is
impossible to have a new lower low
without a new lower high so if we were
to implement the exact same snake trick
you get the head of the snake right here
you follow the body here and as soon as
the movement turns this now becomes the
new lower high that is where the snake
has shifted that is the last lower high
that the market has left now exactly the
same as when the market was bullish this
Market can do absolutely whatever it
wants inside of here as long as we don't
body Candlestick close above or below
the lower high or lower low we will
remain bearish if we decide from this
point right here to then do this we have
created a new lower low meaning we must
need a new lower high and a new lower
high is identified by getting the head
of the snake following it back and as
soon as you get the turn that is where
the new lower high is placed it is very
easy and very straightforward now same
exact thing happens the the moment the
body Candlestick closes above we have
now shifted and now this is a new higher
high this becomes a higher high it is
impossible to have a higher high without
a higher low so then this higher low
will then shift to then this new point
right here this is the simplest and most
advanced version of Market structure
just to identify what the market is
doing because a somewhat experienced
Trader that still hasn't figured it out
just yet can look at this market and be
like oh this Market is in consolidation
this Market is choppy it's an a ranging
Market sure it could be an a ranging
Market but inside of a ranging Market
there is Market structure now what is
the market structure doing is the market
structure bullish or is the market
structure bearish it does not matter if
it is even a market structure that is as
tight as this one right here it can be
in the most choppy movement that you
have ever seen in your life where it is
in the exact same spot for weeks months
years it can be in the exact same spot
forever but there is Market structure
inside of this consolidation move right
here and I want to test you I want to
see if you've been paying attention up
to this point right now pause the video
and tell me inside of that consolidation
is this Market bullish or is this Market
bearish and you know what to make it a
little bit easier I've decided to make
it a little bit bigger so you can go
ahead and take your time and not make a
mistake pay attention to what I just
said now that you have your answer I
want you to know exactly why you have
your answer you might be correct or you
might be incorrect but I want you to
know exactly why you're correct or
exactly why you're incorrect this Market
started off as creating a higher high
and this point down here was then the
higher low as long as we remain above or
under the higher low we will then
continue to be bullish the market body
Candlestick closed at that very point
right there yes something as small as
that counts as a shift of structure
because the market simply did shift
structure so then this becomes the new
higher low this low point right here
that closed under this line then we need
a new lower high it is impossible to
have a lower low without a lower high we
get the head of the snake and then we
follow it up where does it turn right
here this is the snake trick and that is
the new lower high cool as long as we
remain above or under these lines we
will remain bearish we body Candlestick
closed above at this very point right
here where then is has shifted to then
being bullish this is the new higher
high we do the snake trick this becomes
the new higher low at this point point
right here we shifted bearish once again
here now that we've shifted bearish we
do the snake trick it turns and this
becomes the lower high this becomes a
new higher high so on and so forth this
becomes a new higher high after this
point the market did not shift up into
this point this becomes a new higher
high and then this becomes the higher
low body candle stick close under this
now shifts bearish this is now the head
of the snake and if we follow the body
of the snake this is where it turned so
this becomes the lower high and this
Market structure as of right now in this
ranging Market is bearish so if you
answered this correctly make sure you
know exactly how you did it correctly if
you answered it correctly and you didn't
do it like this you simply answered it
correctly without knowing how to analyze
the market correctly so make sure you
write down these notes because it's so
important to executing trades and making
money so now that you understand that to
Perfection because it is very simple I
want to ask you once again another quiz
is this Market bullish or is this market
bearish now pause the video line it up
and why do you think it's bullish why do
you think it's bearish place your lower
high your lower low your higher high and
higher low make a mistake cuz I'm going
to be right here to fix it for you live
go ahead pause the video so now that
you've made a mistake probably or not if
you were paying attention in the last
couple of minutes this Market currently
started off creating a lower low lower
high lower low lower high lower low
lower high lower low lower high and
lower low this is how this Market would
have looked if I would have presented it
to you on the line chart this is how I
see this Market in the Candlestick chart
this Market is inde the bearish and this
point right here is the lower high and
this point right here is now the lower
low it is very simple very straight to
the point until this Market does not
body Candlestick close above this point
or this point there will be no shift in
structure in this market same exact
thing right here this is the lower high
this is the lower low so the market does
not buy the Candlestick close above or
under there is no shift in this market
this Market will remain bearish into
that very point and you want to know the
craziest part that you didn't even know
what time frame this was on you can't
tell if this is on the daily if this is
on the weekly or if this is on the one
minute you want to know the best part
you will never know and I wanted you
guys to identify that market for what
the market is not because it's a crypto
and the crypto's down or because it's a
stock and the stock is strong or because
it's a currency pair and one pair is
stronger than the other that does not
matter when you're reading Market
structure when you're reading Market
structure you're reading Market
structure and that is is it now we are
on to the next Quiz once again pause
this video is this Market bullish or is
this Market bearish Place your higher
highs and place your higher lows or your
lower highs and lower lows so now that
you have placed your higher highs and
higher lows let's see if you're correct
this Market currently at this very
moment started off creating a lower low
lower high lower
low higher high higher low high higher
high and now we have a lower low this
Market went from creating bullish
structure to now shifting to bearish
structure this was the higher low at one
point and this was the higher high at
another the moment the Candlestick close
under this has now shifted to being the
lower low and this has now shifted to
being the lower high reading Market
structure is so essential to
understanding what the market is going
to be doing so you can make an execution
on a trade and make money the best
example that I can put of this is let's
say an experienced Hunter an experienced
Hunter they're going to be able to see
the track of an animal identify what
type of animal it is if it's a male or a
female and if that animal is heading to
the North heading to the east heading
down to rever to drink water whatever
the case is this is what we are looking
at right here we are looking at the
tracks of the market we're able to
identify is this Market going to the
upside is this Market going to the
downside the different types of time
frames let us know the details of the
movement but it's the exact same
movement a hunter can look at a track
and if he looks at it with his vision if
he puts on glasses gets a microscope
takes a picture scans it it's the exact
same track it's just different ways to
identify it so he gets a better idea
what animal it is and what age it has
and what direction it's headed when
we're looking at the market when we zoom
in into the lower time frames and go to
the higher time frames we're looking at
the exact same Market structure just
more details of it so we have a better
understanding of how much more can this
move go how long can we have on our
stop-loss on a takeprofit where should
we see this going within a week within a
month is this Market even actually going
going to go there we're just looking at
the same movement just in a little bit
more detail so with reading the market
structure correctly you're going to be
able to understand where the market is
headed and then there you can decide
what you're going to do is it the right
time to execute a trade should I wait or
do I need something else for the market
to happen for me to execute a trade
perfect example is the hunter the hunter
can see what type of track it is let's
say he identifies that it's an elk and
you could tell by the size of the
footprint that it's a very big male elk
but the elk elk is headed up a mountain
and usually Elks when they head up a
mountain it's to eat food but for at
night time they come back down again I'm
not a hunter this is just a theory but
at that very moment of you looking at
that track it's early in the morning
does it make logical sense for you to go
up that mountain behind the elk or
should you wait till a little bit later
in the afternoon and wait for it to come
back down the mountain so then you can
go and proceed your shop once the elk
comes to you this is the exact same
thing in the markets when you do Market
structure and you do your top analysis
and you understand if the market is
bullish or bearish you can decide should
I go and chase this market and continue
buying with it or is the market at too
much of a high price or too much at a
low price and wait for a retracement so
then I can execute the trade you
identifying the market structure
correctly will let you know exactly at
what point the market is and you can
make a decision off of that right then
and there which the majority of the time
is going to give you anywhere from a 60
to 75% accuracy on every single one of
your trades and to show you how easy
this is let me show you so right here
you can clearly identify that this
Market structure at this very moment is
bearish this Market was creating lower
low shifted to bullish then shifted
right back to bearish and now we have a
lower high and a lower low making this
market bearish now that this Market is
bearish it is at a lower low now you can
make a decision at this lower low should
I sell at the lowest point this Market
has which in turn if I were to flip this
chart around it is should I buy at the
highest point this Market is or should I
wait for some type of retracement and
when we have this retracement now I'm
getting a better rate on the investment
that I'm making it makes more of a
logical sense so then I have a greater
return that is exactly what Market
structure does and it gives you the
perfect entry point to doing that and I
have this video for you right here which
is the top down analysis video which I
explain to the te on how to use this
Market structure to properly do a top-
down analysis and where and when and how
to execute a trade so you're able to
capitalize off of correctly reading the
market structure Market structure is
only 50% of the problem now how you do
that together with top analysis entry
signal and trading at the the right
times is where you actually make the
money that's what this video is about so
make sure you guys go ahead and check it
out because I break down absolutely
everything for free thank you guys very
much for watching this video all the way
to the end hit that like And subscribe
button and I will see you guys in the
next video